Hello everyone. In this section, I will guide you on the basic steps to find Delta using the GTest Automation tool.
First, I will open this tool.
At the main interface, I will navigate to Analysis Support, and select Check Delta from Database, Save Point.
Here, you will see the fields where I need to fill in the necessary information to operate.
The first is the Analyze path.
Here, I will provide the file path of the file that contains the modules I need to analyze.
In this step, I will have two options.
The first option is to use File Analysis.
This File Analysis is the result of
the report file generated from the TPA Report Generation tool.
It contains a large number of modules.
The Testing Team uses this file for the analysis.
For a smaller number of modules, I will choose Option 2.
Here, I will use a template file to fill in the basic information of the module I need to analyze.
Then, I will input the path of that file into the tool.
(Inputting path)
Now, I will demo the first option.
I will input the path of the analysis.
Here, I have a File Analysis generated from the TPA Report Generation tool.
It contains many modules across various components, including both tested and untested modules.
The tool will process the modules whose MTVerdict value is "Undefined".
The tool will support us to analyze those modules.
Now, I copy the path of this file, then paste it into the first field (Analyze path).
(Processing)
The second part is the database path.
This is the path of the folder that contains the database.
Whether loading using Snapshot or Stream,
we will look at our local directory.
Here is the database,
the folder is "DaihatsuCMP".
I will copy this path and input it into the tool here.
Next, I will create a folder.
Here, I will create the "WorkSpace_1" folder.
This folder will contain the files
and documents generated during the tool's process.
Here, I have created the "WorkSpace_1" folder.
At the same time, I also put the File Analysis into this folder.
I will copy the path of this folder.
Next is the Switch Setting part.
This refers to the CSV file generated
in the build config process using Twinset CC.
I will navigate to the database,
go to Gen,
select the corresponding config,
then select Build,
and I will grab the path of this file,
SwitchSettings CSV file.
Then I will input this path here.
Next, I will adjust the parallel threads.
Here, I will have a maximum of 8 threads.
By choosing the corresponding number,
We can help this tool process faster.
It corresponds to the capabilities of this tool.
In the Development Tool section,
they defined the maximum threads as 8,
so I will choose the maximum value of 8 here.
Then I will click Create Delta File.
This is the result after the first step.
Here I have 3 types of modules:
I will have Old, Old and no code, and New.
The result is also shown here.
Relative to New, All, and NoCode,
28 corresponds to New,
16 is All, and 8 is NoCode.
I can observe the running process of the tool.
I can open the Terminal here.
To make it easier to observe, I can split the screen into 2 parts.
To see the detailed results of the modules,
I will go to the "WorkSpace_1" folder,
then I will go to Output,
and select Open Module Info.
Here, I will see all the modules listed.
I have New modules,
Old modules,
and the rest are Old and no code.
The "New" type here refers to the modules
that do not have test scripts in the database
that we loaded from the Stream.
And the "Old" modules here are the ones that have test scripts
and have been tested in the previous version.
Since they already exist
in the current database,
the tool will list them as "Old".
And the "Old and no code" modules are the ones that have the TPA file,
and testing is done.
Those are Old and no code.
The tool helps me to list these modules as Old and no code.
Then, I will build test this file.
First, I will handle the "Old" modules.
Here I choose "Old".
I have 16 modules that are "Old".
Next, I will click Create Folder.
This creates the test folder for these modules.
After step 1, a notification window will appear.
Once the Create Folder step is complete,
we will move to the next step, which is Build Test.
Here, the tool will help build the test folder using the test scripts copied from the database.
After completing step 2, the tool will report the result here.
Coverage has been automatically collected for all modules.
To see the result,
we check the files.
Take a look at the Details page.
We go to Module Info.
Here is the result.
We have data like this.
First is Success.
The second is Fail.
The third is Fail.
When we check the results,
we will see the successful modules with C0, C1, and MCDC coverage at 100%.
This one.
And here we have the modules that have Failed.
Currently, we have failed modules listed here.
These failed modules will be handled in the next steps.
We will test these files.
For the failed modules, we will use the Auto Default Object feature to resolve them.
We will click on this button
for the 15 failed modules.
In this step, the tool will support us in finding the missing objects
in the header files
of the
test script copied from the database into the newly created folder.
Here we can see the number of failed modules
out of the total number of modules.
Currently, we have 15 failed modules.
In total, there are 16 modules.
We will repeat the steps.
(Repeating steps)
After applying the Default Object feature,
we will check the status.
Successful is 14.
Fail is 1.
Total is 15.
After that, we will proceed to Repair Test Suite
to fix the failed modules.
(Processing...)
After this step, the result will appear in this popup. I will have 15 successful, 0 failed, out of a total of 15.
Then I will go to the review step for the failed modules, to verify the results for the modules I have just finished.
(Reviewing failed modules)
Then I will repeat the same steps.
I will also copy the contents for the modules.
That's all.
After finishing the review, I now have 11 successful modules and 4 failed modules out of a total of 15.
To see the details, I will open the Module Info file here.
At the beginning, I only had 1 successful module and 15 failed modules.
Currently, I have 12 successful modules with coverage results for C0, C1, and MCDC represented in 3 columns.
Here.
But I still have 4 failed modules.
Here, I have successfully supported the "Old" modules.
Now, I will move to the "New" modules here.
Currently, these new modules do not have test scripts in my database because they weren't tested in the previous version.
So, I will find the test scripts on the server.
I will search for the test scripts used for these modules in other projects, streams, or snapshots.
I will find them on the server.
Now, I will test this module.
(Testing module)
In the server's information column, I can see project details for the new modules released.
Now, I will input all the test script sources into the server's test script directory.
Now, I will add tags to the basic core functions.
Now, enter the description for the server.
This is the CPU side of the UT Team.
We have the folder for the test.
Here we have the region and the customer.
Then we have the inner folder which contains the stream
or the snapshot, if there is one.
Then we have the build config folder,
and the test environment folder.
Inside the test environment folder, we have the test scripts for those modules.
If we feel that there are not enough modules, we will fetch the test environment.
Then we take the support link before accessing the database.
Then we will put it into the tool.
Then we will load the database.
We select the database,
(Processing...)
as you want.
Here we have the customer,
project.
Right now I'm demoing
the DMC project,
so I'll choose DMC
as the root folder.
Then,
to analyze the new modules
here,
(Processing data)
I'll choose "New".
Here we have 2 options.
The first option:
I'll search each module
separately.
In this section,
I have to fill in
the information like the module name,
so I can find
and search for that module.
Or I can choose
Search New Module.
Here I'll choose All Modules
instead of New.
It will list all the information for me
at once.
I'll go to
select the first module.
Here I have
the new module.
I'll choose
the new module
here.
Then
I'll input the name
of that module
into All Modules.
Then I'll click
Search File.
(Searching file)
then I'll
select
the new module.
Then
I'll click
Search
File.
Right now,
I'm going to
select
the new
module.
Then I'll click search.
And here, after completing this step,
I see that there are 4 tests completed for that module.
In that module, I have checked the test environment.
The name of the stream and the snapshot, as well as the PP number, are displayed in these 3 columns.
Now I will choose a test to refer to the current module.
I will choose this one.
I want to download the test script back, so I will create a folder for downloading.
I have created a download sample folder here.
In this folder, I will copy the folder path.
Then I will right-click on the test that I want to download.
Then I will choose the download folder,
and paste it in the path field.
Then I click Execute.
I will go to the next step, which is to create a folder for that module.
(Processing...)
It's in the folder category.
Then I click Create Folder for that module.
This is the new downloadable module.
After that, I will build test for that module.
To see the details, I open the Module Info file here.
Then I will see the module where I just downloaded the test Delta. The result after running the tool shows the status is Failed.
Then the next step is to define the remaining objects in the module.
(Processing objects...)
(Loading...)
(Please wait for the process to complete)
(Processing...)
After this step, we will have a result here: successful is 4, total is 5.
Then we will go to the next step, Repair Test Suite.
The result is successful is 5, total is 5.
(Repair Test Suite)
(Processing...)
After this step, we will have a result here, successful is 4.
Then we will go to the next step, Repair Test Suite.
The result is successful is 5, total is 5.
Now, it has been changed from FAIL to SUCCESS.
I check C0, C1, and MCDC coverage.
And this one.
After checking all the steps, I can see that there are still 4 modules that have failed.
Then I can choose the test data.
The test module has been tested in this way.
Then I will download the test scripts from the previous version for those modules and build them again.
And see the results in this file.
Here I have finished the demo for everyone.
About the first option in the case of Analyze,
I input the information of the Analyze file here.
Then after this step, I will demo another option.
I will use a Module List file.
What will it be like?
I will open this file.
To use another file, I will create another workspace folder.
I call it "workspace 2".
Here I will have a file called Module List.
Here I have a sheet called Merge Report.
Here I will define the files that contain the information,
to provide data that the tool can work with.
You can see the instructions here.
The yellow sections contain the information the tool has to fill,
and the blue sections are the optional parts.
You can also see the information in the sheet example
so that you can see the format of the data that needs to be filled in.
In this file, it is like this.
Then the data that I need to fill in is like this,
so that I can Analyze it.
It will be in the system report here.
Currently, I have a list of modules
of the components listed here.
Then I will use this file
to analyze the modules that need to find data.
I will copy this list.
Copy this file path.
Then I will input it into the Analyze bar.
Then I will use the database here.
The database I will input is
Workspace 2.
And the switch setting,
I will use the same switch setting as before.
Here I will not change the switch setting.
Then I will click on Create Delta File.
In here, I will see the information.
After running, I will have 2 types of modules:
One is New and the other is Old.
I see it here.
Let's see the information here: New is 4, Old is 10.
To see the information in detail, I will go to the Output folder.
I will open the Module Info file here.
Then I will see that there are 4 New modules and the remaining 6 are Old, corresponding to 10 modules here.
(Reviewing modules...)
Here I have one more feature called Run All Steps.
In this step, I will combine these 3 steps, I will run them continuously, so I no longer have to press each step separately.
Now I will demo the Run All Steps feature.
It will include the Create Delta File step,
Create Folder, and Build Test.
At the same time, at this step, I will choose Old.
To build test, it will build the Old modules for me.
It is the same step, I will choose Old modules to be built.
(Selecting Old Modules...)
Then I will execute.
(Executing build...)
Old modules will be built.
(Processing...)
After completing Run All Steps,
I check the Module Info file.
(Opening Module Info...)
Here I will have 1 module that has Failed,
and 9 successful modules
with the results of C0, C1, and MCDC coverage
like this.
The rest, I will have 4
modules that are New here.
Next, I will handle these New modules.
I will switch to New,
then I will select the relevant information
in the server's section.
In this step, I will demo how to search for new modules on the server.
That is, I will search all the modules
that have the type of New,
listed in the Excel file just now.
I have 4 modules that need to be searched on the server.
While waiting for the tool to run, I will
create a folder
for downloading the scripts
from the server.
I have created a folder like this,
then I will copy the folder path.
After running, I will see that there are 4 modules
that have been found.
I found that there are test scripts on the server.
Then here I will see the modules
that have been tested previously.
And here I will see the modules
that have been fully tested.
Then I am going to load this module.
I will check if it has
the test environment data.
If the test environment
is included inside,
then I will choose these.
First I choose this one,
next here,
then finally, click download.
(Downloading...)
Next, load 1 more module.
Module
I'll demo them one by one.
Again, go back to my existing output.
Then I will choose Create Folder for these two modules.
I will go to folder to create a new module.
Check again.
Next is the other side.
And then I will build test for this module.
After completing the build test, I will check the result.
(Building test...)
For this module, I can use Auto Default Object, then use Repair Test Suite, and then build the module again, like the first demo.
After running Auto Default Object, I will have a successful result.
This is one of the most successful results.
The total number is my module.
After that, I will go to the step of Repair Test Suite.
Fail here, for the module to be failed.
Then I will go to the next step,
which is about the module to be failed.
I will see the detailed results in the Module Info file.
Then I will open this file,
and I will see that my result is here.
Then it will be successful for this module.
The result of C0 and C1 is 100%.
The result of MCDC is 88%.
That's all.
So that completes my demo on finding Delta modules in Unit Testing
using the Automation Tool.
Thank you for following my demo.